Your heart starts to beat on the 21st day of your intra
-embryonic life.
After three weeks, the first system that truly begins to function,
and will do so for its entire life,
has this capacity to distribute information.
This also means that from the moment the heart beats,
there is an acceleration of the growth process.
Who is the first to truly receive the vital information?
From the heart, the entire neural tube, the whole brain, it is the
engine, it will draw in.
We have a very important relationship between the heart and the brain, on a
functional level.
It gives strength to the brain now.
They know each other very well, to the point that even now a study has shown that in the
ventricular system,
in the deep system, there is a direct pulsatile vibration.
with the heart, which informs the brain.
There is a direct link
on very subtle levels.
And so also dependent on another type
of information, because the heart
what does it do? It distributes.
But what does it distribute? It distributes food.
And where does the food come from? Your
digestive system and the relationship with the mother.
You bring in information
organized by your heart,
redistributed by your system. So,
what are you ultimately dependent on,
You are dependent on your digestive system, in your thinking system,
in your development system, as we saw, autocrine, paracrine, digestive,
and only then will the system appear.
When we work on this bond with a child, very often I will treat the
mother.
If the mother is not free in her function, the child cannot free itself either because it will be dependent
on a minimum energy level.
until the age of 7. In its function, on the cellular energy level, all the cells in your body
at 7 years old are renewed.
So you have what we call the new body. It is their first birth, it is the moment when they can reason.
It is the moment when their frontal sinus opens and this heroïde becomes completely electric
because it has re-informed its heart.
That is why we can sense the heart from a distance, because it is informed by the neural crest and it has given its information.
This time now, I can defend myself in my environment. At 7 years old...
I find my first independence.
The outline of the heart appears in the splanchnic mesoderm
on a primitive level.
Again, it will be dependent on the entire yolk system as well,
on everything that is here.
Here we find a presumptive force of the heart,
look at my primitive line,
in the epiblast before gastrulation,
before the vascular plan,
along the cardiogenic epiblast cells,
with all its field of possibilities.
When I take a sacrum or a coccyx and integrate it into
the system, I already have the story of the heart coming forward.
So I must begin to treat the heart by starting to liberate the primitive line under
this first wave that is developing.
When I have my hand, there is already a break in symmetry that takes place during
the establishment of the notochordal process.
There or there, you see, with here.
Below, we have seen that there was a nodal flow that indicated there would be an
information
where there are little cilia that bring cerebral vesicles from
the right to the left via the
shh, the FGF8, the chordin, but ultimately
a change of retinoic acid, that is, a
change on a calcium level which gives a different integration in genetic information.
This means that in the end, I have a break of asymmetry from right to left,
where already important information is given at this level.
This break in asymmetry will be one of the factors that positions my heart to the left in the future,
with morphogenetic molecules, ultimately with an increase in
calcium levels across a lateral plate that will be formed here, and thus all the internal
genetic information will be different. And already this asymmetry
occurs between, one could say,
the base of the skull and the sacrum. And with this primitive line, if
you wish. The deviation is here,
it's a flow that comes from right to left. It
is again found on another level,
through follicular nourishing cells that release enzymes creating
a polarity within the oocyte in the cytoskeleton which means I already have
a first polarization occurring on a cranio-caudal and dorso-ventral level, except it's not yet informed by
its external environment, and we find that the point of entry of the spermatozoon
will create
a re-informing along the longitudinal axis of the embryo where I have this presumptive force
that
will create this integration
is already an external information through the power of the spermatozoon
that restructures the force of the cytoskeleton in a plan
almost electromagnetic.
And some describe that this is found in an embryo within
its apical part.
This means that I capture a field of presumptive information.
And this is how in this presumptive field, I will find...
The future cardiogenetic phase.
The sperm, somewhere here,
is already, in a way, the cardiac force.
The pulse is being prepared there.
But there is no form yet here.
That is why it is a preform.
And then we will quickly see that you will have finally
the whole organization of your embryo
with the famous OLA that will develop.
With finally a...
support point here and a support point here with my primitive line here and with the
re-integration of this system. The importance of this point already
and this
point. The second point will be the moment when I have the
wave, that is to say
the passage of the establishment of my third embryonic chamber,
that is to say what we call the coelom or the external lecithocele which
will reorganize the embryo and make it
have an S-shaped structure but at that moment this is where I will
have the integration relative to the attachment point and that is what gives my line
primitive in an embryo where the heart is there it
makes this the heart has found its place
it has integrated the pericardium it has integrated the
transversal septum with its diaphragm pillars that will be there and will
become a support point for my cardiac system
this means that treating a heart is
to release the diaphragm, since its orientation causes this.
So the diaphragm becomes really our therapeutic tool,
since the pericardial cells are the same cells
that will be found in the plan of the transversal septum,
that is to say, the diaphragm.
Where do they originate?
Above your heart.
I have my heart, and there are small cells,
which are the mesenchymal cells,
which will form my diaphragm.
The ectoderm grows vastly there.
and it balances, and it will form all this system.
The sperm arrives, and you have the key here.
We can meet.
The pill has killed the concept, has killed the possibility of conceptualizing.
We cut off the hormonal system for years.
And now, increasingly, women,
they have difficulties having children.
There is a medical level that has risen,
and we said, now we can help you.
We do what we call...
IMSI, we take a needle, and we prick and penetrate the membrane.
If we are in the right place regarding polarity, it will take.
Except we don't have the first recognition, which is a membrane recognition,
which is a tissue recognition, which is a molecular recognition.
Probably, they will have more and more fertility problems.
Thus, they will no longer know how to reproduce or recognize themselves.
We have removed...
the first recognition these children who come for consultation we have to
recognize them
we have to recognize them at what level of the body their heart we need to connect
with them
through the gaze into their heart if you do this you will see that the child knows that it is the only
thing you can give I can recognize you and help you to be reborn otherwise these people will be
searching their whole life sometimes like this it already happens in your primitive vascular system
Fifth day, finally fifth, sixth, what happens?
The zygote must have metabolic power in a specific pole.
This means that the cellular trophoblast must transform into a syncytiotrophoblast.
This means that this syncytiotrophoblast has a lytic activity to penetrate the
mucosa.
If the embryo does not have this power, it cannot enter its mucosa.
Secondly, the mother must be...
welcoming. But it is not she who does the work for the embryo. Has he
received this power? I remind you that his metabolic power is determined
first by a phase of cellular dedifferentiation. That is, during the
first three or four days, the zygote does not grow. However, it increases its
cell division rapidly, I have an overall increase
of my membrane
and I have a slight water loss outside. This is where it will create this first
cavity we call
the germ of heaven, the blastocoele, which is a specific connection, your outer sky.
And then on the cellular level, I will have an increase in my membrane.
So if I have an increase in my membrane, what do I increase?
Exchange, since membranes, what are they?
They are exchange spaces, always polarized.
If I have a cell, I have a nucleus and I see that my nucleus is never centered.
It is always here, so it is here that I have my greatest exchange power.
Instead of having five,
50, I will have 3000.
Cells in this division phase become 200 times smaller
than the two original blastomeres.
Relatively, I have an increase in my membrane.
If I take my membrane relative to my two first blastomeres,
let's say it’s 100 meters.
If I take all this little membrane, I increase it enormously.
I increase my metabolic power.
If I have sufficient metabolic power, I have sufficient force to enter.
And this metabolic power, I will...
need it for my entire life it’s a bit like the battery you will receive
and you have to trust
that it regenerates to a certain point through your sleep by
your diet through your
breath through your right thoughts etc you see if you don’t respect that
and if you
poison yourself you actually lose essential substrates of this power that are held
there so you need this
Thus the heart already takes its origin practically in the contact of the sperm,
in this meeting, symbolically we can say.
Then we find it at the level of my primitive line.
Then an information already from cardiac fields that will occur here
in relation to the place of a UDN-Sense and in the wave of growth
of the development of cardiac fields.
And then we will see something that is very important.
It is all this developmental movement.